ALEXANDER GRABOWSKI

CONTACT

- https://xangrab.com/
- https://github.com/XanGrab/
- 西 https://github.com/XanGrab/

PROFILE

I have been professionally developing games for the last two years, and recreationally my entire life. I am proficient in a diverse range of full-stack toolchains targeting game and web development. I can frequently be found in international fan games. hackathons, and game jams, expressing my passion for applied learning games and FOSS. I developed a sense of leadership early, achieving the rank of Eagle Scout, and continued developing my leadership skills guiding competitive e-sports teams to compete at the national level. I am a lifelong, self-driven learner and problem solver.

SKILLS

- Game Engines
 - Unity
 - Godot
 - Phaser
- Graphics Libraries
 - Pixi.js
 - HLSL (Unity)
 - GLSL (Three.js)
- · Programming Languages
 - o C++
 - o C#
 - TypeScript
- · Web Development Tools
 - Node.js
 - Vite
 - Webpack
- DevOps & Services
 - Github Actions
 - Docker
 - Firebase BaaS
- Digital Illustration & Wireframing
 - Figma
 - Illustator
 - Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

Gameplay Programmer at Field Day Learning Games 2022.01–2023.05

https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/

♦ Developer and junior designer on multiple projects including *Wake: Tales* from the Aqualab, client-side API for *Open Game Data*, and samller browser-based HTML5 games

Head Programming Instructor at Code Ninjas

2020.10-2022.12

https://codeninjas.com/

♦ Developed programming curriculum for kids of various backgrounds in the K-12 age range spanning JavaScript, MakeCode Arcade, Roblox Studio, and the Unity game engine

Youth Esports Coach at XP League

2020.10-2022.12

https://www.xpleague.com/

⋄ Certified youth eSports coach through the Positive Coaching Alliance. Led the Sun Prairie league's Fortnite team to compete at the North American Finals 2022

PROJECTS

MOTHER².

Unattached

2021-pres

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWeF1jRstLk

Released in 1994 as MOTHER 2 in Japan and as EarthBound in the west, MOTHER² is a full-length ground-up reimagining of the game by fans for fans.

WAKE: TALES FROM THE AQUALAB.

Field Day Learning Games

2022-2023

https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/play/wake/

An oceanography game targeting Chromebooks in middle school classrooms helping students learn scientific experimentation, modeling, and argumentation.

- \diamond Designed pivotal story and level layout elements of the introductory sequence for the game
- ♦ Brought gameplay systems to life in Unity, implementing user interfaces for the game's Shop, Observation Tanks, and Modeling
- ♦ Used in-house scripting tools to implement over seventy-five percent of the quests in the game

UNANNOUNCED HTML5 BROWSER GAMES.

Field Day Learning Games

2023

https://github.com/opengamedata/opengamedata-js-log/

Point-and-click, browser-based games targeting mobile tablets and other handheld devices.

- ⋄ Built data analytics and logging tools for real-time data collection with Firebase in collaboration with the Open Game Data project
- ♦ Developed the game's dialogue system building text-parsing tooling which extended scripts written in YarnSpinner
- Adapted the game's graphics to make use of both WebGL and Canvas rendering styles to meet different tablet and mobile limitations

EDUCATION

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN CAPSTONE CERTIFICATE

University of Wisconsin—Madison

2023-pres.

2019-2023

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Wisconsin—Madison

♦ Certification (minor) in Game Design

- ⋄ Certification in Digital Art
- Certification in Professional Japanese Communication